

# PAUL KNOPF

dad/surfer/musician/engineer

- □ pauldotknopf@gmail.com
- **Q** (941) 807-5340

- pknopf.com
- github.com/pauldotknopf
- twitter.com/pauldotknopf

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

I am a passionate engineer and exceptional problem solver, doing what I love for a living.

I have an intimate understanding of the SDLC, with strong leadership skills that enable me to be effective. I have led and scaled large teams for mission-critical systems, establishing architecture, processes, and best practices to ensure quality and reliability.

With a strong emphasis on simplicity, low ceremony, and an understanding of team capabilities, I ensure that my solutions are built-to-last and move fast based on changing requirements; while also ensuring that even junior engineers can contribute and be effective.

From an individual contributor perspective, my expertise includes a deep understanding of the full stack, encompassing infrastructure provisioning, security/networking, application development, testing, deployment and observability. I'm always learning and keeping up-to-date with the latest technologies and best practices.

I manage a few open-source projects in different languages, including JavaScript, C# and Go.

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### General

Architecture/Design

Networking

Security

Mentoring/Speaking

Agile/Scrum



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Lead Engineer

#### **Ensemble Health Partners**

Aug 2022 - Present

- Led several teams/initiatives.
- Established an ecosystem of libraries, frameworks and pipeline templates to enable rapid development/deployment of various workloads (microservices, Azure resources, terraform, etc).
- Rollout of kubernetes clusters, established the process for teams to deploy/mantain/monitor their workloads.
- Design/implementation/rollout of a micro-frontend client-side architecture, enabling teams to develop modules locally and deploy them into a single integrated clientside application.
- Design/implementation/rollout of Temporal for orchestrating workflows, combining new/legacy systems, creating new use-cases.
- Design/implementation/rollout of CQRS pattern, addressed upper performance limits of our current architecture, resulting in dramatic performance improvements, and significant savings through database SKU optimization.
- Regular presentations to the company on new technologies, best practices, and architecture.

### **Technologies used:**

```
Architecture .NET Core Microservices Dapper/OrmLite Kubernetes React/TypeScript

Micro-frontends Temporal Azure DevOps Azure Terraform ElasticSearch Postgres

Redis
```

### Technical Lead

**Novanta Surgical Imaging** 

July 2019 - Aug 2022

Managing a team of people on a wide-array of projects across different languages/platforms.

### Some key points:

- Overseen design/implementation of next-generation perscriptive architecture/platform for medical imaging software.
- Protobuf/gRPC microservice architecture with a focus on performance and stability, emphasis on golang.
- Cooridination with firmware team to ensure driver/software development feature parity.
- ASP.NET (and .NET Core) React application/MVC APIs, multi-tenancy, on-site deployments with automated updates.
- Established usage of IDesign's "The Method", an approach for system and project design.

### **Technologies used:**



# Senior Software Engineer

Med X Change

Nov 2012 - July 2019

Thought leader for a small team of developers in the embedded and web space.

### Some key points:

- Manage IT infrastructure for software (build agents, on-prem GitLab, etc) and project management.
- Embedded .NET Core runtime in native executable, integration interop with V8.
- iOS/Android application development using the Xamarin platform.

- ASP.NET WebAPIs for consumption in mobile platform.
- DirectShow and gstreamer for encoding/decoding with various video formats, including H264/MP4.
- WPF and Qt/QtQuick implementations of digital recording software on embedded devices.
- C++/C for internal libraries used to connect to record video and connect to hospital networks (DICOM/HL7).
- Custom Embedded Linux distros for embedded devices (Yocto).
  - o Brickless update design.
  - Read-only boot with tmpfs overlay for stability and resilience.
- Compilation and cross-compilation (vc++, gcc, MAKE, CMAKE, meson, autotools, etc).

### **Technologies used:**



## Software Engineer

## MethodFactory

Jun 2011 - Dec 2012

- Managed/maintained production instances of IIS/SQL Server for many high-volume sites (coleman.com, rawlings.com).
- Managed a prescriptive framework written in C# .NET 4.0 used to accelerate and model application development according to industry best practices.
- Managed an internal automated NuGet feed (using TFS Build) for delivering updates.
- Database design and development. Managing indexes/performance.
   Troubleshooting with SQL Profiler.
- Created a process to managing SQL Server Database Projects (SSDT) so that framework libraries can be distributed with matching .dacpac files for client schema updating/generating. The process also included automated deployments of database schema and projects from TFS builds for Continuous Integration and validation of the build.
- Wrote and managed C# TFS Build Activity that creates and deploys multiple NuGet packages.
- Implemented an enterprise WCF Service Host Factory that uses IoC (Dependency Injection) to resolve contracts for runtime composability.
- Created WCF Services using REST/JSON for use on client side widgets.

- Created an MVC3/jQuery eCommerce UI foundation for eCommerce websites.
   Delivered to projects in a .zip file delivered by a VirtualPathProvider for easy updating and ensuring stability. Added support for overriding at every level (css/js/view) for client specific adjustments using a MVC ViewEngine and a client-side dependency management framework (Cassette).
- Implemented/created a jQuery plugin in ASP.NET MVC3 to enable extensible keyboard navigation with 100% client-side interaction from the point of entry.
- Designed enterprise N-tier framework to be reused by multiple enterprise clients (Coleman, Nuk, Rawlings).
- Designed/developed software for medical equipment for capturing and recording pictures and videos using MSMQ/NServiceBus/SignalR to send messages between the website and hardware.

## Technologies used:

.NET ASP.NET MVC SQL Server TFS Microsoft Test Manager

Microsoft Commerce Server Windows Server 2008/2012 Microsoft BizTalk

## Freelance Software Engineer

### **Adept Web Studios**

Jun 2009 - June 2011

- Re-wrote nopCommerce from WebForms to ASP.NET MVC. Contributed it back to nopCommerce for the V3+ release.
- Design and develop custom solutions from cms to e-commerce using the appropriate technologies.
- Created a Lucene.NET implementation for faceted searching in eCommerce solutions (nopCommerce).
- Wrote and sold plugins and themes for nopCommerce.
- Wrote a CMS integration for nopCommerce to bring advanced CMS technologies to an eCommerce driven website.

## Software Developer

#### **Dataline Associates**

Sep 2009 - Aug 2011

- Managing catalog and orders (25,000 products) using MSMQ to handle product/inventory updates.
- Integration into 3rd party websites for price comparison and analytics.

 Managing web server (Windows Server 2008 R2) and database for high-uptime and high-load.

## **PROJECTS**

## 

An integration of .NET and QML for cross platform and high-performance desktop applications. I built a thin C layer with C++ shared pointers to integrate the two garbage collectors (.NET and QML-JavaScript). AppVeyor and Travis CI are configured to ensure a suite of tests pass for each commit on every major platform (Linux/OSX/Windows).

# **Technologies used:**



## 

Think "Dockerfiles", but for immutable, stateless, graphical (or not) environments, booted bare-metal. I use this tool as my daily driver for Linux. Each distribution contains a custom initramfs that overlays a temporary file system over your read-only Darch images. This allows each boot to be a clean boot. Any change made to the runtime (apt-get install, etc) are discarded on each boot. Any change you want persisted has to be scripted and baked into your recipes (which is a good thing!).

# **Technologies used:**



# Technologies used:



# **EDUCATION**

# MCPD/MCTS .NET Web Developer

MCP ID: 8482776

## **Associates of Liberal Arts and Science**

State College of Florida.

GPA 3.6 2008-2010